

Abhishek Gupta

Details

Lancaster
England
+44 7833460266
abhishek.gupta0724@gmail.com

Portfolio Link

Abhishek Gupta

Skills

Python

Machine Learning Models

R

Deep Learning

MySQL

Oracle

C#

Communication skills

IT Project Management

Collaboration

About Me

With a professional experience of 4.5 years, automation and data-related issues have been my forte. I have a rich experience in the field of retail planning where I honed my skills in Databases, scripting languages, and consulting. Currently pursuing a Masters's in Data Science, I intend to explore the field of Machine Learning and make an impact.

Work Experience

Data Science Intern, Crux Intelligence, India

JANUARY 2022 - JULY 2022

- Developed and Integrated Crux's search engine(Ask) to Microsoft teams as a conversational BOT. The bot was developed on the BOT Framework SDK in python and further deployed on Azure as a service.
- 2. Engineered performance-related issues for the Natural Language Processing module.
- 3. Developed code in ANTLR to analyse key performance metrics for customers.

Technical Analyst, Blue Yonder (JDA Software), India

JUNE 2017 - JULY 2021

- 1. Responsible for solving data-related issues within the customer database like SQL and Oracle.
- Developed an in-house automation tool Hygiea, which cut down 600 hours/month of manual efforts. This dashboard helped me explore the front-end and back-end aspects of a project and get hands-on experience with Angular JS, C#, HTML/CSS.
- 3. Worked as a deployment analyst for our Products services which helped me hone my project management skills. This responsibility involved planning from implementation to delivering the environment while interacting with the customer and our internal teams.
- 4. Lead the problem management initiative by working on various performance-related database issues and performing Root Cause Analysis for the same. The work comprised modifying SQL Scripts like stored procedures, functions, triggers, and database-related constraints like stats gathering and table re-indexing.
- 5. Delivered training programs in Shanghai for our consulting partners and conducted webinars regarding product features.

Education

Masters in Data Science, University of Lancaster, England

OCTOBER 2022 - SEPTEMBER 2023

Currently pursuing my Master's in Data Science with a major in advanced Machine Learning models, Distributed AI, and Big Data Systems.

Bachelor of Technology, PES Institue of Technology, India

AUGUST 2013 - MAY 2017

Pursued my bachelor's in the field of Telecommunication engineering and successfully secured a CGPA of 8.29

Certification

Information Technology Infrastructure Library, Version 2